ALEX KIM

ALXK.IO | PROVIDENCE, RI | AKIM06@RISD.EDU | +1 917 891 5667

Dear Gretel,

Hello, my name is Alex and I am currently an undergraduate student pursuing a BFA in Graphic Design with a concentration in Computation, Technology, and Culture at the Rhode Island School of Design in Providence, Rhode Island. I was reinstated into RISD in the Fall of 2022 after having left the institution in Spring of 2008. I was originally part of the class of 2009 but am currently set to graduate in Winter of 2023.

While my academic career has been quite a winding road, in between leaving RISD and ultimately deciding to return, I had spent almost 12 years building a career in the restaurant industry as a chef. Foregoing culinary school, I went straight into the industry, progressing very quickly from a small restaurant in Durham, North Carolina to the ranks of Michelin restaurants in New York City, San Francisco, and Kyoto, Japan. My experience culminated with the opening of a restaurant for a publicly traded Japanese outdoor company in Portland, Oregon.

Currently I am pivoting back into a career in design, with an interest specifically in UX Design & Strategy although UI & Typography are of course of central importance to me. I also have a great interest in coding having taking online courses in Computer Science separately and enjoy coding my own websites.

I am currently seeking an internship specifically in the NYC area. My portfolio can be viewed here, which is continuously being updated with new work. Thank you for your time!

Sincerely,

Alex Kim Graphic Design Undergraduate CTC '23 Rhode Island School of Design

ALEX KIM

ALXK.IO | PROVIDENCE, RI | AKIM06@RISD.EDU | +1 917 891 5667

EDUCATION

RHODE ISLAND SCHOOL OF DESIGN, PROVIDENCE, RI

SEPTEMBER 2006 - MAY 2008, SEPTEMBER 2022 - DECEMBER 2023 Currently pursuing a BFA in Graphic Design Concentration in Computation, Technology, & Culture (CTC)

POMONA COLLEGE, CLAREMONT, CA

SEPTEMBER 2005 - MAY 2006 Liberal Arts Studies

LANGLEY HIGH SCHOOL, MCLEAN, VA

SEPTEMBER 2005 - MAY 2009

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

MAD ACADEMY, BUSINESS & LEADERSHIP PROGRAM, COPENHAGEN, DENMARK

OCTOBER 2020

Intensive program for rising leaders in the Hospitality and Food Industry focusing on the need for functioning leadership in hospitality. Hosted by MAD Academy from chef René Redzepi of restaurant Noma and chef Magnus Nilsson of Fäviken. Attendee by invite to the inaugural session.

EXPERIENCE

UNTITLED.HAUS - FOUNDER & SOLE PROPRIETOR

DECEMBER 2020 - CURRENT

Online store for design, gastronomy, and art related media.

TAKIBI, SNOW PEAK, INC., PORTLAND, OR - EXECUTIVE CHEF

FEBRUARY 2020 - AUGUST 2021

Opening Chef for flagship restaurant, Japanese brand Snow Peak U.S. Headquarters.

KIKUNOI HONTEN, KYOTO, JAPAN - STAGIER

SEPTEMBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

Three Michelin Kaiseki Cuisine in Gion-Maruyama. Chef Yoshihiro Murata.

KAPPO SAKAMOTO, KYOTO, JAPAN - COOK

APRIL 2017 - JULY 2019

One Michelin Kappo Cuisine in the Gion District. Chef Ryuta Sakamoto.

RINTARO, SAN FRANCISCO, CA - SOUS CHEF

AUGUST 2015 - MARCH 2017

California-Japanese Cuisine. Chef Sylvan Mishima Brackett.

BENU, SAN FRANCISCO, CA - COMMIS

JULY 2014 - AUGUST 2015

Three Michelin Modern Asian. Chef Corey Lee.

KAJITSU, NEW YORK, NY - LINE COOK

AUGUST 2012 - FEBRUARY 2014

Two Michelin Shojin Ryori, Kaiseki Cuisine. Chef Ryuta Ueshima.

LANTERN, CHAPEL HILL, NORTH CAROLINA - LINE COOK

JULY 2011 - JULY 2012

YAMAZUSHI, DURHAM, NORTH CAROLINA - COOK

MAY 2010 - JUNE 2011

INTERNSHIPS

NARU SOBA, HAMAMATSU, SHIZUOKA PREFECTURE, JAPAN - STAGIER

AUGUST 2017

Internship at a soba restaurant.

SOBA RA, HONJO, SAITAMA PREFECTURE, JAPAN - STAGIER

FEBRUARY 2016

Internship at a rural soba restaurant by invitation of author Nancy Singleton Hachisu.

MAINE SEAWEED, STEUBEN, ME - INTERN

APRIL 2014 - JULY 2014

Harvesting and processing of various Atlantic Seaweeds.

ROMERO FARMS, DIXON, NM - INTERN

MARCH 2009 - SEPTEMBER 2009

Internship at an organic farm in Northern New Mexico.

AWARDS & HONORS

WASHOKU WORLD CHALLENGE, 8TH COMPETITION

DECEMBER 2020

Finalist + Winner for an International Japanese Cuisine Competition organized by the Japanese Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry, and Fisheries.